Aniket Pradhan

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

🛮 +91 98975 00297 | 💌 aniketpradhan1999@gmail.com | 🥻 aniket-pradhan.github.io | 🖸 github.com/Aniket-Pradhan | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/ap9989

Personal Profile

A nerd working at Adobe, as a Software Development Engineer. Currently working on the Streaming workflows in the Adobe Experience Platform, to segment billions of different "profiles" within minutes. Zealous about Research and Development, with a few publications at major conferences around Optical Network Communication. Fascinated by Machine Learning and Data Engineering roles.

Work Experience ____

Adobe Noida, India

Member of Technical Staff, Member of Technical Staff - 2

Jul 2021 - Feb 2023, Feb 2023 - Present

- At Adobe, I am a part of the Unified Profile Services team, inside the Adobe Experience Platform, where I work on the <u>Streaming Segmentation</u> and Edge Segmentation workflows.
- The work revolves around providing real-time segmentation for billions of user profiles around the world with minimal latency as low as in milliseconds.
- Segmentation is the process of identifying certain traits or behaviors shared by a subset of profiles to distinguish a marketable group of people from the customer base.
- Technical Skills: Scala, Apache Kafka, Apache Spark, Microsoft Azure, gRPC

Adobe Noida, India

Product Intern May 2020 - July 2020

- As a Product Intern, I worked on a closed domain question and answering (QnA) framework, using the state-of-the-art methods of natural language processing.
- The QnA framework was designed to be flexible and modular, suitable for Adobe Experience Platform's Documentation.
- Technical Skills: Python with Tensorflow and PyTorch XLA (for Google TPU), Git.

RealVol New Delhi, India

UI Designer Intern May 2018 – July 2018

- At RealVol I worked on the design and the UI for the product, RealVol
- Technical Skills: Unity VR, C#, Git.

OutWorx Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Noida, India

Android Developer Intern

June 2018 – July 2018

- Created and implemented simple animations for Android.
- Implemented scalable widgets for Android Applications.
- Technical Skills: Android Studio, Java, Kotlin

Education

Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology - Delhi

Delhi, India

B. Tech in Electronics and Communications Engineering

Aug 2017 - May 2021

• Courses: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Speech Recognition and Understanding, Game Design and Development, Software Development using Open Source, Digital Audio, Digital Image Recognition

May 27, 2023

Father Agnel School

High School

2015 - 2017

- Passed with Distinction
- Specialised in Physics, Chemistry, and Maths with Computer Science

University Projects

Efficient Filling of C+L Bands for an Optical Network

Delhi, India

Indraprastha Insitute of Information Technology - Delhi and British Telecom

May 2019 - May 2020

- Studied the non-linear effects faced by optical signals in a multi-hop path.
- · Analyzed link margins in an optical network and studied the methods to reduce them in a backbone optical network.
- Compared the benefits offered by a multi-fiber optical network and a multi-band optical network.
- Technical Skills: Python, LaTeX.

Deep Neural Network Based Predictions of Protein Interactions using Primary Sequences

Delhi, India

Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology - Delhi

Oct. 2018 - Feb. 2019

- Created a tool in Python to automate data collection and organize the data in a pretty SQL table.
- · Worked on and implemented Deep Structured Semantic Network (DSSM) in Python using Tensorflow
- · Worked on an approach to simplify querying of similarity based protein sequences, using supervised methods
- Technical Skills: Python with Tensorflow, SQL.

IoT Smart Lock

Delhi, India

Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology - Delhi

Dec. 2017 - Apr. 2018

- Automated lock which can be controlled securely via the Internet.
- Provides a key less access to the lock with a robust and modular tech stack.
- Secure communications between the clients and the host using TLS 1.2
- Technical Skills: C, Python, Arduino.

Publications

- T. Ahmed, S. Rahman, A. Pradhan et al, "C to C+L Bands Upgrade with Resource Re-provisioning in Optical Backbone Networks", 2021 Optical Fiber Communications Conference and Exhibition (OFC), 2021, pp. 1-3.
- R K. Jana, A. Mitra, A. Pradhan et al, "When Multiband Elastic Optical Networks Becomes More Economical Than Multifiber Elastic Optical Networks?", European Conference on Optical Communication 2020, DOI: 10.1109/ECOC48923.2020.9333276
- A. Mitra, D. Semrau, N. Gahlawat, A. Pradhan et al, "Capacity Benefits of Operation Over C+L Band Elastic Optical Network in the Indian Network Scenario", IEEE ANTS 2019, DOI: 10.1109/ANTS47819.2019.9117992

Posters_

• A. Sinha, A. Pradhan, Q. Fang et al, "Comp-NeuroFedora, a Free/Open Source operating system for computational neuroscience: download, install, research", Org. for Computational Neurosciences 2020

Skills.

Programming Miscellaneous

Java, Scala, Python (Tensorflow, PyTorch, NumPy, Pandas etc.), C/C++, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL.

Linux, Shell (Bash/Zsh), Apache Kafka, Apache Spark, Apache Flink, ŁTĘX, Git.

Soft Skills

Ownership, Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Engaging Presentation, Report writing, Product Design, Logical Thinking

Design, Logical Thiriking

May 27, 2023 2

Positions of Responsibilty

- 2020 **Byld Admin**, Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology Delhi
- 2019 **Web Admin**, Summer Camp @ Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology Delhi
- 2019 **Volunteer**, Summer Camp @ Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology Delhi
- 2018 **Web Admin**, Research Showcase @ Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology Delhi
- **Event Head**, Student Breakthrough, Research Showcase @ Indraprastha Institute of Information 2018
- Technology Delhi
- 2018 **Event Head**, RoboWars, ESYA @ Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology Delhi

Languages

English Professional proficiencyHindi Native proficiencyFrench Bilingual proficiency

May 27, 2023